justin clark

Full stack developer with insatiable desire to learn & grow. I believe there is great beauty in simplicity, and I strive to keep things simple in web design, user experience, and the codebase. My best quality is adding quality value.

Seattle, WA
www.justinclark.dev
github.com/justinclark-dev
linkedin.com/in/justinclark-dev/

EDUCATION

North Seattle College, Seattle, WA — AA in Programming

JUNE 2018 - PRESENT

EXPERIENCE

Walt Disney, Seattle, WA

Full Stack Developer

AUGUST 2015 - JUNE 2018

- Developed a web UI with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.
- Built a frontend infrastructure using Node.js/Express.js on Linux.
- Implemented application failover using Forever.js for server restarts.
- Stored UI session data in mongoDB allowing node app restarts.
- Implemented SSO and enterprise-level security using SAML.
- Implemented version control using git and GitLab.
- Developed a Continuous Delivery pipeline using git pushes.
- Managed QA on production releases to UI.
- Created Bash scripts for analyzing codebase to reveal unused code.
- Covered all three roles after two teammates left the team.
- Worked with business segment customers to resolve bug tickets.
- Implemented Jira Ticket creation directly in internal reporting website.
- Revamped, reconfigured, and managed Jira instance for my team.
- Refactored business logic improving maintainability, performance.
- Created and maintained Confluence instance for site documentation.
- Developed new features to solve client's business needs.
- Automated database updates using SSIS, PowerShell, and Excel.
- Persuaded management to allow rebuild of backend infrastructure.

Business Operations Analyst

APRIL 2009 - AUGUST 2015

- Developed internal app called Wall-E using VBA to organize reports.
- Converted Wall-E app from MS Access into ASP.Net website using VB.
- Developed MS Access app for storing and processing vendor invoices.
- Co-developed internal dashboard website for 3rd party ad reporting.
- Ensured continuity of service during multiple server migrations.
- Used VBA programming to automate reports in Excel spreadsheets.

FRONT END

- Angular
- HTML5
- CSS3
- SASS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript

BACK END

- Node.js
- Express.js
- Bash
- ASP.NET
- PHP

DATABASES

- SQL Server
- MySQL
- MongoDB

TOOLS

- NPM
- Git
- GitHub
- GitLab
- Confluence
- Jira

OS

- Linux
- MacOS
- Windows

RECENT BOOKS

Clean Code, Uncle Bob